Guide to the Alice L. Hageman Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Organizations Served, Series IV
  - World Student Christian Federation
    - Board of Trustees and Senior Friends
      - Senior Friends gathering in Montreal - program and reports, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Trustees meetings and communications, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Second Century Fund / WSCF Centennial Fund, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - Trustees meetings and communications, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Senior Friends addresses, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Regarding renewal of WSCF North America Region and Student Christian Movement in the U.S., 2009-2010 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Trustees meetings and communications, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence regarding tax-exempt status of WSCF, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 5)
        Enclosures include Certificate of Incorporation of Trustees of the WSCF, By-Laws, IRS documents
      - Trustees meetings and communications, 2011 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Trustees meetings and communications, 2012, 2014 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Committee of Returned Volunteers
    - Organization and policy records
      - Chronologies and statements of purpose for CRV, 1966-1969 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
      - Meeting and committee records, 1966 November - 1967 June (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Meeting and committee records, 1967 July - 1968 February (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Meeting and committee records, 1968 March - December (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Meeting and committee records, 1969 January - September (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Meeting and committee records, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Operating procedures, 1969, no date (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Membership lists, 1967-1971 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Financial and fundraising records, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Issues and activities
      - Miscellaneous events and position papers, 1967-1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Africa-related events and statements, 1966-1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Election and inauguration protests and statements, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Latin America / Cuba issues, 1967, no date (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Peace Corps / right of dissent, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Vietnam / Southeast Asia war - CRV position paper on Vietnam, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Vietnam / Southeast Asia war - Mobilization on Washington, 1967 October (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Vietnam / Southeast Asia war - miscellaneous protest documents, events, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
      - Vietnam / Southeast Asia war - Thailand packet, no date (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Publications
      - Brochures about CRV, No date (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - National CRV newsletter, 1967-1971 (Box 9, Folder 5-8)
      - Regional newsletters (Minnesota, New York), 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - CRV journal: "Two...Three...Many", 1970 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Others
    - Church of the Covenant, Boston / Field education program Andover Newton Theological School, 1975-1980 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Cuba Resource Center, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Ecumenical Foundation for Higher Education in Metropolitan New York, 1966-1968 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    - Mid-Atlantic and New England Conference on China and the United States, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Notes, correspondence, agendas, and lists of participants in the "Conversation on China" organized by Alice Hageman to discuss issues of politics and development in contemporary China
    - Women's Campus Ministry Caucus: correspondence, statements, 1969-1972 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Women's Campus Ministry Caucus: newsletters, 1972-1974 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Women's Campus Ministry Caucus: background material on women in ministry, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 7-9)
    - World Council of Churches, Commission on World Mission and Evangelism, 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
- Personal and Collected Material, Series V
  - Subject files
    These files are a sampling of material collected by Alice Hageman on a variety of subjects. They provide a glimpse of her range of interests.
    - Ecumenism (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Latin America (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Social justice issues (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Student Christian movement (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Women's and gender issues (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence
    These correspondence files are fragmentary but provide a sense of Hageman's circle of friends and areas of interest. Addtional correspondence related to her activities is located in other series.
    - Including with Association Press regarding Hageman's books Religion in Cuba Today and Sexist Religion and Women in the Church., 1957-1978 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Including undated letter from Margaret Flory, 1978-2008 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Biographical material
    - Clippings, notes, schedules, 1967-2004 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of AH (Box 12, Folder 4)